Brad Bieselin

Wantagh, NY | 516-557-8407 | brad@bradbieselin.com linkedin.com/in/bradbieselin | GitHub | Blog | bradbieselin.com

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in React, JavaScript, and Ruby on Rails based programming with a background in Computer Science and Project Management. Possess strong skills in architecture design and project management that help software and technology companies. Computer Science graduate with experience in both professional and educational environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord, REST APIs, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Pair-Programming, Agile, Styled Components, Tailwind, SEO, Amazon Web Services, WSL 2, VS Code/Studio, IntelliJ, Project Management

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Spats - Github (Frontend) | Github (Backend)

Spotify stats tracker where users connect their Spotify account to the application to track their account stats

- Collectively built a full stack project with two peers at Flatiron School using React and Ruby on Rails
- Integrated the Spotfiy Web API to authenticate user login and gather data
- Associated data in the Rails API to compare previous user data to current user data
- Blueprinted the application design using Styled Components

Taskier - Github (Frontend) | Github (Backend)

Task management app that allows users to manage their tasks and due dates.

- Programmed the frontend with React and the backend with Ruby
- Built a full CRUD API with ActiveRecord and Sinatra
- Implemented dark mode and designed the application using styled components and React Hooks
- Leveraged the ORM for SQL queries and migrations

Cash Prize Photo Challenge - GitHub | Demo

Users upload images based on a challenge category, then get votes to win the challenge.

- Collaborated with another engineer to develop an interactive single-page React application
- Utilized the useState hook to dynamically update the application and set up controlled inputs, allowing for the creation of new submissions and updates to vote counts
- Established data fetching using the useEffect React hook to render submissions, vote count, and to post new submissions or update votes in the database
- Styled the application using Styled Components to create an appealing user interface

EXPERIENCE

Witbe Inc New York, NY 06/2021 - 04/2022

Project Manager/Customer Success Manager

- Led and managed 9 projects for customers including Verizon, ViacomCBS, and Peacock by automating VoD asset testing, Channel Change testing, and video/audio quality analysis, promoting business growth by over 40%
- Prepared and facilitated 8+ hour interactive training sessions for customers, including 10+ senior executives on delivery of new products and software

Apple Remote Software Quality Engineer 02/2021 - 06/2021

- Automated test cases in Java using Jackson, Jenkins, TestNG and Gradle for over 3000 scenarios
- Gained fluency in AWS with 40+ hours of training and obtained AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote

15-Week Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

04/2022 - 07/2022

University at Albany, SUNY Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Albany, NY 05/2015 - 12/2019